<?xml version="1.0" encoding="Windows-1252"?>
<LanguageManager>
    <Translations>
        
        <Translation Key="P1 Welcome">
            <English>Welcome at the Pendulum Experiment. Get used to the experiment: deflect the pendulum with drag and drop.</English>
            <German>Willkommen beim Pendel-Experiment. Mach dich vertraut. Lenke das Pendel mittels Drag and Drop aus.</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P1 Ropelength">
            <English>Well done! Now use the Mouse wheel to adjust the rope length.</English>
            <German>Sehr gut! Jetzt verwende das Mausrad, um die Seillänge zu verändern</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P1 Weight">
            <English>Nice! Now use 'A' and 'D' on your keyboard to adjust the mass.</English>
            <German>Super! Jetzt verändere die Masse mit den Tasten 'A' und 'D'.</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P1 Stopwatch Start">
            <English>Perfect! Now start the stop watch by clicking on it.</English>
            <German>Perfekt! Jetzt zur Stoppuhr: Klicke darauf um sie zu starten.</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P1 Stopwatch Stop">
            <English>Now stop it by klicking it again.</English>
            <German>Und jetzt stoppe sie wieder, indem du abermals darauf klickst.</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P1 Timelaps">
            <English>Wow! You found the time laps function! This will come in handy during the experiment!</English>
            <German>Wow! Du hast die Zeitlupe gefunden! Sie wird beim Experimentieren sehr nützlich sein!</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P1 Moveon">
            <English>Great! Click on 'Let's go' at the white board.</English>
            <German>Sehr gut! Klicke auf 'Los gehts!' am Whiteboard.</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P1 Easteregg">
            <English>(Watch out: There is still an easter-egg hidden!)</English>
            <German>(Achtung: Es gibt noch ein Easter Egg!)</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P1 Start">
            <English>Awesome! Let's move to the next chapter, shall we?</English>
            <German>Sehr gut! Kann's los gehen?</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="Lets Go">
            <English>Awesome! Let's move to the next chapter, shall we?</English>
            <German>Sehr gut! Kann's los gehen?</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 Exercise">
            <English>Exercise 1: calculate the Frequency of any pendulum
Adjust the length and mass of the pendulum as you wish. Try to measure the period 3 times, calculate the frequency and insert your values here.
I'm going to support you as best as I can.</English>
            <German>Aufgabe 1: eine Frequenz eines beliebigen Pendels zu messen/errechnen
Stelle dazu das Pendel auf beliebige Länge und Gewicht. Versuche, 3 mal das Pendel zu messen und trage deine Ergebnisse hier ein.
Ich werde dich so gut es geht unterstützen.</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 Ropelength">
            <English>Length of Rope (cm)</English>
            <German>Länge des Seils (cm)</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 Weight">
            <English>Mass (kg)</English>
            <German>Masse (kg)</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 MeasuredTime">
            <English>Measured Time (s)</English>
            <German>Gemessene Zeit (s)</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 CalcFreq">
            <English>Calculated Frequency (Hz)</English>
            <German>Berechnete Frequenz (Hz)</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="Check">
            <English>Check</English>
            <German>Prüfen</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 FarDeflected">
            <English>Caution! The simple formula just works for deflection angles lower than 5°</English>
            <German>Achtung! Die simple Formel funktioniert nur für Auslenkungen unter 5°!</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 NoPeriod">
            <English>Caution! This wasn't a period! Your measurement could be wrong.</English>
            <German>Achtung! Das war nicht ganz eine Periode! Deine Messung könnte falsch sein.</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 GoodCalc1">
            <English>Awesome! your calculation misses the theory by a margin of</English>
            <German>Sehr gut! Deine Berechnung liegt um nur</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 GoodCalc2">
            <English>Hz</English>
            <German>Hz neben der Theorie</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 BadCalc1">
            <English>I'm sorry, that's not correct. Please check these things:</English>
            <German>Das ist leider nicht ganz korrekt. Prüfe folgende dinge nach:</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 MisCalc">
            <English>you probably miscalculated,</English>
            <German>du hast dich wahrscheinlich verrechnet,</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 TimeMeasure">
            <English>your time measurement is not as exactly as it should be,</English>
            <German>deine Zeitmessung scheint nicht genau genug zu sein,</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="P2 WrongRopeLength">
            <English>your given rope length is not equal to the current rope length,</English>
            <German>deine angegebene Seillänge stimmt nicht mit der derzeitigen überein,</German>
        </Translation>
        
    </Translations>
</LanguageManager>