<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<LanguageManager>
	<Translations>
		<Translation Key="DescriptionTitle">
			<English>Description</English>
			<German>Beschreibung</German>
		</Translation>
        <Translation Key="DescriptionAStar">
            <English>A*(A Star) is an algorithm that uses distance to prioritize what path to search next, reducing the number of steps needed.
We start by looking at all neighbors from the player position, and since they are exactly 1 step away from the player, we save this and call it f. Now we estimate the distance for all of them to the goal, and call it g.
Next we look for the tile with the lowest combined f + g, called h, will be selected next. For all neighbors of that tile, we again now know that it takes 1 additional step to get there. We repeat this process until the goal is one of the neighbors, in which case we have found a path.</English>
            <German>A* ist ein Algorithmus der die geschätzte Distanz nutzt, um die Suche nach dem Ziel zu beschleunigen.
Man startet damit, die benachbarten Felder zum Spieler durchzugehen, und da diese 1 Schritt vom Start entfernt sind, merken wir uns das als f. Nun schätzen wir jeweils die Distanz ab, und merken sie uns als g.
Als nächstes suchen wir das Feld mit der niedrigsten gesamten f + g, auch genannt h. Für dieses Feld wissen wir wieder, dass die Nachbarn 1 Schritt weiter vom Start entfernt sind. Dieser Prozess wird wiederholt solange, das Ziel einer der Nachbarn ist, womit ein Pfad dorthin gefunden wurde.</German>
        </Translation>
        <Translation Key="PathfindingAlgo">
            <English>Pathfinding Algorithm</English>
            <German>Pfadfindungsalgorithmus</German>
        </Translation>
        <Translation Key="NumberOfElements">
            <English>Maze Size</English>
            <German>Labyrinthgröße</German>
        </Translation>
        <Translation Key="Speed">
            <English>Animation Speed</English>
            <German>Animationsgeschwindigkeit</German>
        </Translation>
        <Translation Key="TileInspector">
            <English>Tile Inspector</English>
            <German>Kacheln ansehen</German>
        </Translation>
        <Translation Key="TileCoords">
            <English>Tile Coordinates</English>
            <German>Kachel Koordinaten</German>
        </Translation>
	</Translations>
</LanguageManager>