<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<LanguageManager>
    <Translations>

        <Translation Key="EnterNoiseExperiment">
            <English>Welcome! Here you can get to know how perlin noise works. Try out different types and experiment
                with the values.
            </English>
            <German>Willkommen! Hier kannst du über Perlin Noise lernen. Probiere verschiedene Typen und Werte aus.
            </German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="Type">
            <English>Type</English>
            <German>Typ</German>
        </Translation>

        <Translation Key="ShaderType">
            <English>Shader Type</English>
            <German>Shader Typ</German>
        </Translation>

        <Translation Key="Scale">
            <English>Scale</English>
            <German>Skalierung</German>
        </Translation>

        <Translation Key="Octaves">
            <English>Octaves</English>
            <German>Oktaven</German>
        </Translation>

        <Translation Key="Size">
            <English>Size</English>
            <German>Grösse</German>
        </Translation>

        <Translation Key="Flatness">
            <English>Flatness</English>
            <German>Ebenheit</German>
        </Translation>

        <Translation Key="Threshold">
            <English>Threshold</English>
            <German>Schwelle</German>
        </Translation>

        <Translation Key="Smoothness">
            <English>Smoothness</English>
            <German>Glätte</German>
        </Translation>

        <Translation Key="PerlinNoise">
            <English>Perlin Noise</English>
            <German>Perlin Noise</German>
        </Translation>
        <Translation Key="Configure">
            <English>Configuration</English>
            <German>Konfiguration</German>
        </Translation>

        <Translation Key="ConfigureVoxel">
            <English>Configuration Voxel</English>
            <German>Voxel Konfiguration</German>
        </Translation>

        <Translation Key="ConfigureMarchingCubes">
            <English>Configuration Marching Cubes</English>
            <German>Marching Cubes Konfiguration</German>
        </Translation>

        <Translation Key="DescriptionPerlinNoise">
            <English>Perlin Noise is a type of <b>gradient noise</b> that can be used to create infinite continuous pseudo-random values. These values can be manipulated by the seed, scale or octaves. The <b>seed</b> is used to initialize the random generator, &lt;b>scale&lt;/b> scales the x-axis and <b>octaves</b> adds multiple layers of noise.</English>
            <German>Perlin-Noise ist eine Art <b>Gradientenrauschen</b>, das verwendet werden kann, um unendliche kontinuierliche Pseudozufallswerte zu erzeugen. Diese Werte können durch den Seed, Skalierung oder Oktaven manipuliert werden. Der <b>Seed</b> wird verwendet, um den Zufallsgenerator zu initialisieren, <b>Skalierung</b> skaliert die x-Achse und <b>Oktaven</b> fügt mehrere Schichten hinzu.</German>
        </Translation>


        <Translation Key="DescriptionVoxel">
            <English>The Vertex mesh gets generated by separating the grid cubes whose noise values are above and below the threshold with a mesh.</English>
            <German>Das Vertex-Mesh wird generiert, indem die Gitterpunkte, deren Rauschwerte über und unter dem Schwellenwert liegen, mit einem Mesh getrennt werden.</German>
        </Translation>
        <Translation Key="DescriptionMarchingCubes">
            <English>Marching Cubes is an alorithm for creating a mesh by separating the corners of the gridpoints that are above or below the threshold with a mesh. The mesh can be smoothed by interpolating the position by the vertex values.</English>
            <German>Marching Cubes ist ein Algorithmus zum Erstellen eines Meshes durch Trennen der Ecken der Gitterpunkte, die über oder unter dem Schwellenwert liegen, mit einem Mesh. Das Mesh kann geglättet werden, indem die Position durch die Eckpunktwerte interpoliert wird.</German>
        </Translation>
        
        <Translation Key="Options">
            <English>Options</English>
            <German>Optionen</German>
        </Translation>

        <Translation Key="Description">
            <English>Description</English>
            <German>Beschreibung</German>
        </Translation>

    </Translations>
</LanguageManager>
